Finding Aid for Helen Milliken Papers 1965-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical files, 1969-1982
  - Sex Education
    - Miscellaneous (proposals, legislative testimony, etc.), 1975-1981 (Box 8)
  - Sleeping Bear Dunes, circa 1974-1982 (Box 8)
  - Smith College (Box 8)
  - Soil Conservation Society of America, Michigan Chapter (Box 8)
  - South African Divestment, circa 1982 (Box 8)
  - Special Commission on Architecture
    - The State Building Process: Analysis and Recommendations, November 21, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Special Commission on Art in State Buildings
    - Agenda and minutes, 1976-1981 (Box 8)
    - Correspondents, undated; 1977-1981 (Box 8)
    - Memoranda, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
    - A Program to Integrate Art and State Buildings. Report, October 1977 (Box 8)
    - Clippings (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (especially fundraising and legislative materials) (Box 8)
  - Special Olympics (Box 8)
  - Teaching-Learning Communities, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Telephone Lists (unidentified) (Box 8)
  - Tennis (legislation concerning and correspondence-recreational), 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - Thank You's
    - 1979-1982 (Box 8)
    - Christmas, 1979-1982 (Box 8)
  - Trapping, 1976-1982 (Box 8)
  - Traverse City. News Summaries, August 27-September 5, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Welfare, 1982 (Box 8)
  - White House Conference on Families, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Willoway Center for the Performing Arts, circa 1977 (Box 8)
  - Wolves, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Women, Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1974-1981 (Box 8)
  - Women. "We, the Women ..." Wayne State University. Conference, June 11-13, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Women In Communications Brunch, circa 1975 (Box 8)
  - Women of American Native Tribes, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Women's Health Service, Detroit, Michigan (Box 8)
  - Women's Issues (Republican and Democratic Platforms), 1980 (Box 8)
  - Women's Resource Center
    - Grand Rapids, Michigan, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Traverse City, Michigan, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Wood Energy in Michigan. An Analysis of Impact and Alternatives to the Plant at Hersey, Michigan, March 26, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Youth for Understanding, 1973-1977; 1 linear feet
    The Youth for Understanding files within the Topical Files series total ca. 1 linear foot of historical items, agenda, minutes, resolutions, correspondence, memoranda, grants, and reports and proposals documenting the activities of this international teenage exchange program.
    - Historical Material
      - Bylaws (Box 8)
      - Organizational Charts (Box 8)
    - Meetings
      - Board of Trustees (Agenda, Minutes, Resolutions, etc.)
        - 1973 (Box 8)
        - 1974 (Box 8)
        - 1975-1977 (Box 8)
      - Executive Committee (Minutes, Memoranda, Reports), 1976-1977 (Box 9)
      - Executive Staff (minutes), July-August 1974 (Box 9)
      - Notes on European Meeting, Amsterdam., May 10-12, 1974 (Box 9)
      - Program Council (scattered minutes and calendar), 1974-1976 (Box 9)
      - Transcript of meeting with R. Andersen, S. Fleming, P. Yasinski, N. Shine, and J. Crippen present., May 23, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence
      - 1973 (Box 9)
      - 1974 (Box 9)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 9)
      - 1977 (Box 9)
      - 1978, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Memoranda, 1973-1977 (Box 9)
    - Reports and Proposals
      - National Committees and the Program Council, undated (Box 9)
      - Highlights, 1972 (Box 9)
      - Brazilian Intensive English Program. Final Report, April 19, 1976 (Box 9)
      - Summary Reports, June 1976; May 1977 (Box 9)
      - Relocation Proposal, circa 1976-1977 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous Reports, circa 1973-1977 (Box 9)
    - Publications
      - Compass, No. 1 and 3 (Box 9)
      - Intercom, Vol. 1, No. 1 and 2 (Box 9)
      - News from the House, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Grants
      - International Bicentennial Courier Project. American Revolution Bicentennial Board, 1975 (Box 9)
      - International Teenage Student Exchange Program. Lilly Endowment, undated (Box 9)
      - Printed Material (Box 9)
    - Program Materials (Box 9)
    - Financial Statements, Auditors Reports and Memoranda, 1973-1975; 1981 (Box 9)
    - Project Statistics (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - Zero Population Growth (Lansing area membership list), June 1974 (Box 9)
    - Zonta (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1969-1992; 1.5 linear feet
  Correspondence covers the period 1969-1982 and measures ca. 1.5 linear feet of files. The correspondence has been arranged chronologically. As items are often attached, they have been filed chronologically by the date of the top letter. The Correspondence Files supplements other correspondence found throughout the Topical Files and the Appearances Files. Effort was made, however, to bring together within the Topical Files correspondence relating to Artrain, International Women's Year, the Michigan Council for the Arts, and Youth for Understanding.
  - Undated, 1969-1975; 11 folders (Box 9)
  - 1976-1981, 18 folders (Box 10)
  - 1982, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Appearance Files, 1965-1982; 7 linear feet
  Helen Milliken's Appearance Files are arranged chronologically and include correspondence, administrative request forms, printed materials, clippings, and miscellanea.
  - May 26, 1965-October 26, 1971 (Box 11)
  - November 4, 1971-October 26, 1974 (Box 12)
  - December 10, 1974-November 14, 1977 (Box 13)
  - December 16, 1977-January 31, 1980 (Box 14)
  - February 1, 1980-March 31, 1981 (Box 15)
  - April 1, 1981-December 16, 1981 (Box 16)
  - January 6, 1982-June 30, 1982 (Box 17)
  - July 1, 1982-December 16, 1982 (Box 18)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series is arranged by topic and is most extensive for images on the Artrain. In addition, there are photographs of William Milliken and political events that Helen Milliken attended. Also of note is a folder of photographs relating to trips to China and to Russia.
  - Art in State Buildings, Governor's Special Commission on (Box 19)
  - Artrain
    - circa 1971 (Box 19)
    - 1972 (Box 19)
    - Plymouth, 1972 (Box 19)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 19)
    - Undated (Box 19)
  - China and Russia (Box 19)
  - Cunningham, DeVon (Box 19)
  - Groups (Box 19)
  - Head Start (Box 19)
  - Kalamazoo views (commissioned by Kalamazoo Institute of Arts ), 1979 (Box 19)
  - Milliken, William G (Box 19)
  - Political events (Box 19)
  - Portraits (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    (includes Dorothy Comstock Riley portrait)
  - Artrain albums
    - [brown], 1971 (Box 19)
    - [white], circa 1972 (Box 19)